<?xml version="1.0"?>
<swl:swl xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
     xmlns:swl="https://www.dfargo.com/ns/swl"
     xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
     xmlns:rss="https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification"
     xs:schemaLocation="https://www.dfargo/com/ns/swl /schema/swl.xsd">
  <rss:item>
    <rss:link>https://www.dfargo.com/page/websitelooks/post.html</rss:link>
    <rss:title>Keeping a simple site</rss:title>
    <rss:pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 13:54 CDT</rss:pubDate>
    <rss:author>fargodre@grinnell.edu (Andrew Fargo)</rss:author>
    <rss:description>My site looks like it was made in the mid-oughts. But why?</rss:description>
    <rss:category>meta</rss:category>
  </rss:item>
  <article>
    <p>
      As I&apos;m rebuilding this site, I feel its worth answering this question for
      myself and for those who are curious. I think it comes down to a few reasons:
      accessibility, ease of writing, and
      preference. I&apos;ll try my best to explain what I mean.
    </p>
  
    <h2>Accessibility</h2>
    
    <p>
      I&apos;ll preface this section by saying I&apos;m not, by any metric,
      an expert in accessibility.
      <em>It is important that we all be mindful of accessibility.</em>
      Folks smarter than me
      have demonstrated time and again that accessibility, in addition to making systems
      remotely tolerable for some, benefits everybody.
    </p>
    
    <p>
      I&apos;m working on a separate, better researched post about web accessibility.
      In the meantime, it suffices to say that concise, machine-readable HTML is
      the most feasible way for me to keep this site accessible.
    </p>
    
    <h2>Ease of writing</h2>
    
    <p>
      Secondly, I write pages like this by hand.
      I&apos;ve used tools like jekyll, org-publish, and tex4ht
      in the past for writing blog posts, but I find that it&apos;s just too difficult or
      inconsistent for my purposes. I much prefer having control over
      the page&apos;s markup.
    </p>
      
    <p>
      Thus, for a similar reason to accessibility, keeping the HTML simple
      and semantic is one of the only feasible ways to do this.
      I don&apos;t want to hand-write fifty divs, or copy and paste
      templates to that effect.
    </p>
    
    <p>
      A nice benefit of hand-writing these pages is stability.
      It reminds me of when you visit an old BBC page and you&apos;re teleported back to the 2000s;
      as long as the filepaths stay the same,
      this page can sit unchanged.
    </p>
    
    <h2>Preference</h2>
    
    <p>
      Finally, I&apos;m just a fan of the late 90s early 00s look.
      It harkens to a time when you didn&apos;t need a mega-corporation in order to make
      a page just about you. (I am hosting this on GitHub, but I&apos;ve written a webserver before
      and want to use it in the future!)
    </p>
    
    <p>
      Nothing beats accessible, timeless simplicity, and I think that&apos;s pretty cool.
    </p>
  </article>
</swl:swl>
